（黄長瀬(きながせ)）ひどいな これは
This is horrible.
That damn Kiryuuin always does
whatever the hell she wants.
（黄長瀬）
鬼龍院(きりゅういん)め まったく好き勝手…
I've arrived, too.
About to enter HQ.
（美木杉(みきすぎ)）僕も着いた
今から本部に入る
Welcome back, Mr. Mikisugi!
（戦闘員）
おかえりなさい 美木杉さん
Is everyone ready?
みんなは？
EPISODE 15
DON'T STOP ME NOW
It's been too long, missy!
（宝多(たからだ)）
ひさしぶりやな 皐月(さつき)はん
You've become quite the babe, I see!
（宝多）また べっぴんさんに
なったんちゃうか？
And you've become
even more loathsome.
（皐月）貴様はますます
げびた顔になったな
Though I can't remember
where our paths last crossed.
どこで会ったかは忘れたが
It was back at the garden party to
celebrate your graduation from grade school.
（宝多）あんたの
小学校卒業記念の園遊会以来や
宝多財閥の御曹司が—
Don't you remember the Takarada Conglomerate's
heir honoring you with his presence?
わざわざ出向いてやったのに
忘れたんかい
（皐月）
その貧相な顔を覚えていただけ
ありがたいと思え
You should feel honored that
I even recognize your seedy face.
（宝多）ハッ 相変わらず
気持ちええぐらい上から目線やな
So you still get off on
lookin' down on everyone, do ya?
If you think everyone you meet's just gonna
do what you say, you're sorely mistaken.
そやけど何もかんも
あんたの思うとおりいく思たら
大間違いやで
The only one who's sorely mistaken is you
for thinking you can stand against me.
間違いは私に逆らう貴様の頭だ
You think you can purchase
human lives with money?
人の命を金(かね)で買うか…
What twisted upbringing
led to your vile methods?
どう育てば そんなに醜く
金が使える？
All's fair in love, war,
and splashin' out the cash!
銭にきれいも汚いもないで
Japan is divided between two massive conglomerates:
the Takaradas in the west and the Kiryuuins in the east.
KIRYUUIN SATSUKI
TAKARADA KANEO
西の宝多 東の鬼龍院いうたら
日本を二分する大財閥や
KIRYUUIN SATSUKI
TAKARADA KANEO
If we don't throw this
money around, who will?!
わてらが金使わんで
誰が使うんじゃ〜
It looks like you've become obsessed
with the power of those strange outfits lately,
最近 妙な服の力に
ご執心のようやが—
but lemme give you the bottom line.
あいにくやったな　見いや！
Look!
For the right price, all these people will
gladly lay down their lives for me in battle!
これだけの人間が銭のためやったら
命を惜しんで戦(たたこ)うてくれる
Regardless of the era,
it's money that motivates folk!
いつの時代も人を動かすんは銭や
That's the power of cold, hard cash!
銭の力や〜
That is where you're mistaken.
それは違うな
What was that? Some kind of bluff?
何や こけ脅かしか？
What I struck was their hearts.
（皐月）
斬ったのは こやつらの心だ
Begone, fools!
Or my next strike will take your lives!
去れ 痴(し)れ者ども 次は命を絶つ
（男性Ａ）ひ〜
（男性Ｂ）こらあかん
She's bad news!
（男性Ｃ）命あっての物種や
（男性Ｄ）さいなら〜
Get out of here while you can!
Bye, now!
We're no match for her!
（女性Ａ）かなわんわ
（女性Ｂ）待って〜な
Wait for me!
Do you see now, Takarada?
（皐月）わかったか宝多
人を制するのは金ではない 恐怖だ
It is not money that rules
the hearts of men. It is fear.
フン それでキメたつもりかいな
You think that little stunt
was enough to beat me?
Cut the empty bravado, Takarada.
Your voice is shaking with fear.
（猿投山(さなげやま)）無理するな宝多
その声色 明らかにビビってるぞ
Oh, I'm scared! I'm scared, all right!
ビビってます ビビってますよ
妙な見栄(みえ)張っても
一銭にもならへんさかいな
Acting tough ain't gonna
make me any cash.
So you won't even
try to be a man, huh?
男のきょうじも見せぬか
つくづく見下げ果てたヤツだ
And just when I thought
you couldn't sink any lower.
You gotta be kiddin'.
ところがどっこい
見上げてもらうことになりまんな
I'm about to rise higher
than ever before!
ウハハハハ どうや？
Say hello to my anti-Honnouji Academy
mechanized weapon, Doutonbori Robo!
対本能字(ほんのうじ)学園機動兵器
道頓堀(どうとんぼり)ロボや
ANTI-HONNOUJI
ACADEMY
MECHNIZED
WEAPON
DOUTONBORI
ROBO
If you're weak, rely shamelessly
on something stronger!
（宝多）自分が弱いときには
見境なく強いもん持ってくる
これがわいの必勝哲学や
That's my foolproof strategy for winning!
Pathetic.
（皐月）くだらん
（猿投山）何という悪趣味な姿
How incredibly tacky.
（宝多）おや…
目も見えへんのにわかりまっか？
Oh? You can tell that
without even usin' your eyes?
（猿投山）ああ
気配だけで十分臭ってくるよ
Yes. I can sense it in the very air—
the stench of your overblown arrogance.
貴様のおごりの臭いがな
（宝多）おごるんは嫌いや
割り勘でいこうやないか
I hate holdin' the check.
What say we go Dutch?
（猿投山）
金の話ではない 心根の話だ
I'm not speaking of money.
I'm speaking of your disposition.
...Your opinions...
（宝多）そんなもん
一銭にもならへんわ！
don't add up to jack!
Club members! Guard Lady Satsuki!
お前たち 皐月様を守れ！
Archery! Javelin!
アーチェリー！ ジャベリン！
Discus! Shot put!
（猿投山）ディスカス！
（部員たち）うぃ〜っす
（猿投山）ホーガン！
（部員たち）う〜っ
Everyone else!
（猿投山）その他！
（部員たち）どすこい どすこい！
うぎゃぎゃぎゃ… スポーツマンが
なんぼのもんじゃ〜
Jocks like you ain't worth one red cent!
（部員たち）
うわ〜 ごっつぁんで〜す
Good match!
How d'ya like this, missy?
（宝多）どうやどうや皐月はん
あんたご自慢の極(ごく)制服も—
Your precious Ultima Uniforms ain't no thing
against the full might of the Takarada Conglomerate!
宝多財閥が本気になったら
相手にならしまへんな
Go sell 'em at the
thrift shops in Americamura!
ぜ〜んぶまとめてアメリカ村の
古着屋に売っ払いなはれ
安う買いたたいたるわ！
They'll take 'em off your hands for cheap!
You dare mock clothing,
despite never having tasted the fear it brings?
服の怖さも知らぬ者が服を笑うか
安いのは貴様の命だろ！
The only thing that's
cheap here is your life!
...As if! Here we go...
ぬかせ！ いくで〜
千成瓢箪(せんなりびょうたん)ミサイルシャワー！
Gourd Missile Shower!
Whaddaya think of my
golden gourd bombardment?
どうや？
金にモノいわした
ひょうたん爆撃や
There's plenty more
where that came from!
まだまだ
なんぼでもあんで
Die! Die! Die!
いね いね いね…
いんでまえ〜！
Die, bitches!
ハァ なんぼ何でもしまいやろ…
ああ？
Nobody could've survived that.
So long as I,
Gamagoori Ira, draw breath,
（蟇郡(がまごおり)）この蟇郡あるかぎり
皐月様には傷１つ付けさせん！
I will not allow so much
as a scratch on Lady Satsuki!
You should quit while
you're behind, Naniwa monkey.
（蛇崩(じゃくずれ)）調子に乗るのも
いいかげんにしなさい なにわ猿
I'll be recording the data from these
new Three-Star Ultima Uniforms.
（犬牟田(いぬむた)）
この新しい三つ星極制服のデータ
取らせてもらうよ
遅くなりました皐月様
My apologies for the delay, Lady Satsuki.
The Kobe and Kyoto Battlefield
Trip Brigades have now arrived.
神戸および京都襲学(しゅうがく)旅団
ただ今 合流いたしました
（皐月）ご苦労
Good work.
Catch, Sanageyama!
（スピーカー:伊織(いおり)）
受け取れ猿投山
Here's your new Ultima Uniform!
（伊織）君の新しい極制服だ！
At last!
（猿投山）待っていた！
はいっ たあっ とう〜！
What's with the cheap hero show crap?
（宝多）何やねん？
その安手のヒーローショーは
（猿投山）ツッコミ無用！
Spare me the commentary!
You face Sanageyama Uzu of the
Honnouji Academy Four Devas!
本能字学園 四天王のうち
猿投山渦(うず) 押して参る
Three-Star Ultima Uniform:
Blade Regalia Mk 3!
剣(つるぎ)の装 更改(さらにあらため)
THREE
STAR
ULTIMA
UNIFORM
BLADE
REGALIA MK 3
てえい！
Oh boy. He really gets into it.
あ〜あ 張り切っちゃって
Subjugating Osaka is his mission.
大阪攻略はヤツの任務だ
奮起するのは当然だろう
It's only natural that
he should give it his all.
北関東の猿 対 大阪の猿
猿の頂上決戦だねえ
The northern Kanto monkey
versus the Osakan monkey.
It's a monkey vs. monkey battle royale.
あら ワンちゃんにしちゃ
ウマいこと言うじゃない
Wow, that's quite insightful
coming from you, doggie.
蛇崩語録の応用さ
I'm simply taking a page
out of your book, Jakuzure.
さすがに蛇 ちらちらとのぞかせる
舌の毒は半端ないからねえ
After all, the venom of the snake's
flickering tongue is powerful stuff.
Gee, thanks.
ありがと
Head! Body! Wrist!
面 胴 小手！ 面 胴 小手！
か〜 千成瓢箪ミサイルシャワー！
Gourd Missile Shower!
Head! Body! Wrist!
面 胴 小手！ 面 胴 小手！
面胴小手 面胴小手 面胴小手…
Head! Body! Wrist!
Head! Body! Wrist! Head! Body! Wrist! Head! Body! Wrist!
What the hell?!
何やて？
フン 貴様の小汚い
ひょうたんのシャワーなど—
Do you think I'll allow you to continue
with that pathetic gourd shower?!
これ以上 浴びるか！
You're finished!
終わりだ！
Head!
面！
な… 何じゃこりゃ！
Wh-What the hell is this?!
That there is crab paste slime!
（宝多）
そいつは蟹(かに)味噌スライムや
一度まとわりついたら
ぜ〜ったい取れへん
Once you get it on you,
it never comes off!
You ain't movin' any more!
あんさんの機動力は封じたで
Now you're finished!
Eat-'til-you-drop Fire!
とどめや 食い倒れファイヤー！
It's baked crab paste for you!
蟹味噌焼きになれ〜！
Flame off!
噴射やめ〜い
Now, let's see if you turned out
golden brown and delicious.
さ〜て おししく焼けたかな〜と
Oh?
あらへんやんけ
He's not here!
（猿投山）貴様の味噌など
かぶる俺だと思ったか
Did you think your
crab paste could coat me?!
...What the—!
（宝多）ああ〜 あへあへ〜
（猿投山）なめんな！
Don't underestimate me!
Thrust! Thrust!
（猿投山）突き 突き！
（宝多）アウチ アウチ
Thrust! Thrust! Thrust!
（猿投山）突き！ 突き！ 突き！…
（宝多）アウチ アウチ… アウチ〜
（猿投山）突き突き突き…
（宝多）あうう うう… アウト〜！
Out!
（宝多）あああ… そこはあかん
あかんて あかんあかんあかん…
No, not there!
Anywhere but there!
Not there, not there, not there!
Thrust!
（猿投山）突き〜！
（宝多）ああ〜ん！
Oh, yes!
I'm dead, I'm dead, I'm so dead!
うう 死ぬ死ぬ 死んでまうがな…
あああ〜
Do you value your life?
自分の命は惜しいか？
Lookin' down on me again, huh?
また見下ろすか ええ気分やろな
You must really be
gettin' off right now.
But this ain't over.
Osaka's all about tenacity and conviction.
でもな これでしまいやないで
大阪者(もん)は粘りが信条や
（皐月）こちらもそのつもりだ
Of course.
My target here was never you.
私が相手にしているのは
貴様じゃない
What was that?
何やて？
Do you think that I would mobilize
a force of this size to fight mere students?
たかだか学生相手に—
これだけの戦力を
投入する私だと思ったか
No... You can't be serious!
まさか 貴様…
Who gave you the power to
stand against Ultima Uniforms?
極制服に対するその力
誰にもらった？
（宝多）ぎゃあ〜
ほう
Looks like you're having fun
throwing your weight around, Kiryuuin Satsuki.
（流子(りゅうこ)）ずいぶんと
好き勝手やってるようだな
鬼龍院皐月
Don't you think wrecking
an entire town's a bit much?
（流子）町１つぶっ壊しやがって
あんまりひどすぎるんじゃないか
（皐月）
そんなことを言うために
ここに来たのか
Did you come all this way
merely to tell me that?
If so, your trip was for nothing.
だとしたら無駄な旅だったな
Their fate was sealed
the moment they defied me.
私に逆らう者の定めは決まっている
（流子）
その定め 私が変えてやるよ
鮮血(せんけつ)を返してもらうぞ
I'm going to change that fate.
You're going to give Senketsu back.
Ah, so this is what you are after.
なるほど これが目当てか
Sanageyama. Dispose of that fool.
猿投山 その愚か者を片づけろ
At once!
Mako, fall back to someplace safe.
マコ 安全な場所まで下がってろ
Kay!
Mankanshoku?
満艦飾(まんかんしょく)…
The rest of you, stay out of this.
（皐月）お前たちは手を出すな
（蟇郡）はっ
Yes, ma'am!
Can you take it back, Matoi Ryuuko?
（皐月）取り戻せるか？ 纏(まとい)流子
（流子）ああ
Yeah.
（流子）
うおらっ うっ えい！ たあ！
I see your defense
is no less impressive.
相変わらず かったいガードだな
And I see your drive is the only thing
that's impressive about you.
気迫だけは一人前だな いいだろう
Very well, then.
The lioness uses her full strength,
even when hunting a rabbit!
獅子はウサギを狩るにも
全力を尽くす！
Life Fiber Override, Godrobe Junketsu!
（皐月）人衣(じんい)圧倒 神衣(かむい)純潔
GODROBE
JUNKETSU
I won't hold back, Matoi.
遠慮はしないぞ 纏
Why isn't the transfer student
transforming?
（蛇崩）
なんで転校生は変身しないの？
Part of her Godrobe is still in
Lady Satsuki's possession.
（犬牟田）彼女の神衣の一部は
皐月様が持っている
神衣が完全覚醒するとき—
When a Godrobe completely awakens,
生命戦維の中を
強力な生体エネルギーが流れる
powerful bio-energy flows
through its Life Fibers.
Any missing part interrupts the flow,
preventing transformation.
１カ所 欠けていれば流れが止まる
覚醒はできないというわけだ
フン この手袋がなければ
人衣一体ができぬようだな
It would appear that you cannot
synchronize without this glove.
You transformed knowing that, huh?
それがわかっていながら
変身すんのかよ
さっすが鬼龍院皐月
容赦ないな！
Typical Kiryuuin Satsuki!
Your ruthlessness knows no bounds!
You challenged me knowing full well
you were at a disadvantage.
（皐月）
不利を承知で
挑んだ戦いのはずだ
Don't whine to me now.
泣き言は聞かぬ
（流子）
そんなことは
言うつもりもねえ！
I'm not whining!
But you are shortsighted and reckless!
（皐月）
が 所詮はただの無謀だ！
It's him! The ripped mohawk dude!
あいつ！ 筋肉モヒカン！
Matoi, run!
（黄長瀬）纏 逃げろ！
Attention! Your objective is the rescue
of Takarada Kaneo and Matoi Ryuuko!
（美木杉）いいか 目的は
宝多金男(かねお)と纏流子の救出だ！
When the mission is complete,
withdraw immediately!
作戦終了次第 速やかに撤退しろ！
Avoid any unnecessary combat!
無駄な戦闘は避けるんだ
Launch all units! Open #4 gate!
（スピーカー:アナウンス）
全機発信 第４ゲート 開け！
Launch all units! Open #4 gate!
（美木杉）とうっ いやっほ
That said, I doubt the good Miss Satsuki
will just sit by and let us do that!
と言ってはみたが—
あの皐月お嬢さんが
そんな甘いことは—
許してくれるわけは
ないだろうね！
Why the change of heart, mohawk guy?
（流子）
どういう風の吹き回しだ？
モヒカン野郎
（黄長瀬）しかたない
お前をバックアップしろと—
I have no choice.
Mikisugi asked me to back you up.
美木杉に頼まれたからな
First you attack me,
and then you protect me?
私を狙ったり守ったり 忙しいな
You must lead a busy life.
（黄長瀬）俺たちの狙いはただ１つ
We have but one objective:
to resist subjugation by the
Life Fibers that Kiryuuin uses.
鬼龍院が使う生命戦維の
支配に対抗せよ
That is Nudist Beach's goal!
それが僕たちヌーディストビーチだ
That name was for real?!
その名前 マジか！
What the hell are you wearing?
何だ？ その格好
I wish I could have kept playing
the lazy teacher forever,
できれば ぐうたら教師を
ず〜っと続けたかったんだけど—
but it looks like
that's no longer possible.
そうはいかなくなったみたいだ
I see you've shown yourselves,
you naked fools.
（皐月）
あぶり出されたな 裸の愚者よ
The true objective of the
Big Three Battlefield Trip
今回の三都制圧襲学旅行の
真の目的は—
was to smoke out the rebel force lurking
in the shadows behind the Kansai academies.
関西の学園の裏に潜む反抗勢力を
あぶり出すこと
That is why Lady Satsuki allowed your
activities to continue, Mikisugi Aikurou!
そのために貴様の行動も皐月様は
黙認していたのだ 美木杉愛九郎(あいくろう)！
Goodness, you saw through me?
How impressive!
うひゃ〜 そこまでお見通しとは
恐れ入るね
I'd expect no less from one of Lady Satsuki's
stratagems. It worked exactly as planned.
さすがは皐月様の作戦
狙いどおりでしたね
Well, it was technically me
who came up with it.
まあ立案したのは俺だけど
We were worried that you'd never show
and our new Ultima Uniforms would go to waste.
そろそろ出てきてくれないと—
せっかく新調した極制服が
使えないところだったわ
Do you think a group with a foolish name
like Nudist Beach can thwart our grand design?
ヌーディストビーチなどと
ふざけた名前の連中に—
我らの大望が阻めるか！
Fade like morning dew
before my Blade Regalia Mk 3!
剣の装 更改の露と消えろ！
Three-Star Ultima Uniforms!
（四天王）三つ星極制服
Shackle Regalia Mk 2!
（蟇郡）縛(しばり)の装 改(あらため)
SHACKLE
REGALIA MK 2
THREE
STAR
ULTIMA
UNIFORM
Symphony Regalia Mk 2!
（蛇崩）奏(かなで)の装 改
THREE
STAR
ULTIMA
UNIFORM
SYMPHONY
REGALIA MK 2
Probe Regalia Mk 2.
（犬牟田）探(さぐる)の装 改
THREE
STAR
ULTIMA
UNIFORM
PROBE
REGALIA MK 2
Blade Regalia Mk 3!
（猿投山）剣の装 更改
THREE
STAR
ULTIMA
UNIFORM
BLADE
REGALIA MK 3
Honnouji Academy
Four Devas Regalia Mk 2!
（四天王）本能字四天王
改の装(よそおい) 四将綺羅飾(きらかざり)
HONNOUJI
ACADEMY
FOUR
DEVAS
REGALIA
MK 2
Four Generals, Dressed To Kill!
FOUR
GENERALS
DRESSED
TO
KILL
（戦闘員たち）うおお〜
（四天王）とお〜
Ryuuko!
（マコ）流子ちゃ〜ん
Mako! I told you to go
hide someplace safe!
（流子）マコ！
安全な場所に逃げろっつっただろ
Yeah, so I came here.
（マコ）だからここに
（流子）え？
The safest place I know
is by your side!
（マコ）流子ちゃんのそばが
いちばん安全だよ
Oh, right.
（流子）そうか
Senketsu, let's transform.
（流子）鮮血 変身するぞ
（鮮血）無理だ
Impossible.
Yes, you may have collected
enough to restore my form,
（鮮血）確かに
これだけそろえば形は復元できる
but without that glove,
the bio-energy cannot flow.
だが あの赤手甲(せきてっこう)がなければ
生体エネルギーが流れない
Make up for what's left
with my own skin.
足りない部分は私の皮膚を使え
No way!
（鮮血）そんな！
生命戦維を流れるエネルギーは—
Human skin cannot withstand the energy
that flows through Life Fibers for even one minute!
人間の皮膚では１分ともたない
One minute is more than enough.
（流子）それだけあれば十分だ
（鮮血）流子
Ryuuko?
You want to be worn by me, right?
So don't worry about me.
（流子）
お前は私に着られたいんだろ
だったら遠慮するな
I'm not scared anymore, either.
私も もう恐れない
If you're my friend,
believe in me like Mako does.
お前も友達ならマコのように
私を信じてくれ
（鮮血）友達か
（流子）ああ
...Friend...
Yeah.
Very well. Let's do it, Ryuuko.
（鮮血）わかった 行こう流子
（流子）おう！
Right on!
Life Fiber Synchronize: Godrobe Senketsu!
（流子）人衣一体 神衣鮮血
GODROBE
SENKETSU
うっ あっ このやろ…
...Son of a...
何だと？
What?
Kiryuuin Satsuki!
（流子）鬼龍院皐月！
This is nothing but pretense!
（皐月）
しかし付け焼き刃に過ぎん！
Are you that eager to die, Matoi?
（皐月）死ぬ気か 纏
Nope! This is how I'll survive!
（流子）いいや ここが活路だ！
What?!
何！
Godrobe Senketsu!
（流子）神衣鮮血
Now I have it all back.
全て返してもらったぞ
Snatching life from
the jaws of death, eh?
（皐月）捨て身こそ死中の活か
Nevertheless,
you still cannot beat me!
だが！ それでもお前は
私には勝てない！
We'll see about that!
それはどうかな！
Your power has increased?
（皐月）
力が上がっている
That's what I'm saying.
（流子）
そういうことだな
It has! Don't underestimate Matoi Ryuuko when she's
concentrating on a goal that's almost within reach!
そうだよ！ 究極に目先の欲に
目がくらんだ纏流子をなめるな！
That fool!
あのバカ
Concentrating on
what's in reach? Pathetic!
（皐月）目先の欲？ くだらん！
Have you forgotten the rampage you went on
when you gave in to the rage before you?
目先の怒りに我を忘れて
暴走したのを忘れたか？
父の敵(かたき)を憎む心を忘れたか？
Have you forgotten the burning fury
you felt for your father's killer?
I haven't forgotten!
But I won't let it drown me!
忘れてない！ だがもう溺れない
二度とあの過ちは犯さない
I'll never make another
mistake like that again!
目先の怒りに自分を見失わずに
目先の欲に生きる
I'll push aside the rage
that confronts me
and live for the desire
of what's almost in reach!
大事な友を取り戻し
大事な友を守るという—
The desire to take back my friend!
To protect the friends
that are precious to me!
目先の欲にな！
That is why you wander aimlessly
through life, bereft of ambition!
それこそ
志(こころざし) 低きに流れるというのだ！
What about your
oh-so-lofty ambitions, then?
（流子）だったら てめえの
高邁(こうまい)な野望とやらは何だ？
Look at this scorched wasteland.
見てみろ この焼け野原を
これがお前の言う野望か？
そのための犠牲か？
Is this your ambition?
A necessary sacrifice?
If this is the way you
use the power of Life Fibers,
これがお前の使う
生命戦維の力だというなら—
Senketsu and I will stop you!
私が鮮血が止めてみせる
もうこんな勝手はさせない！
You've had your way long enough!
If that's the case, prove it to me
not with words, but with action!
だったら言葉だけではなく
行動で示せ！
あっ 流子ちゃん！
Ryuuko!
Senketsu Blade Flash!
鮮血閃刃(せんじん)！
What?!
何っ
Senketsu Gale!
鮮血疾風！
...Why, you...
（戦闘員）この！ ああっ
Lady Satsuki!
（蛇崩）皐月様！
Lady Satsuki, climb onto me!
（蛇崩）皐月様 私の上に
（皐月）おう
Just you watch.
I'll catch up to her in no time!
（蛇崩）見てて
すぐにヤツを捕らえる
だが これでは私より高い目線には
ならぬのではないか？ 乃音(ののん)
Perhaps, but like this, you can
never rise above me. Can you, Nonon?
（蛇崩）フッ バカね
Don't be silly.
（流子）あっ
（皐月）纏流子！
Matoi Ryuuko!
...Why, you...
Damn it!
Lady Satsuki!
（蛇崩）皐月様！
How impertinent!
（皐月）こざかしい！
（皐月）うおお〜
（流子）何！
What?!
（流子）がはっ
Let's go, Jakuzure. Let's finish this.
いくぞ蛇崩 一気にキメる
Leave it to me.
（蛇崩）任せて！
Matoi!
纏！ うっ
Now, now. I'd like to collect some
combat data for my Probe Regalia Mk 2.
（犬牟田）
おっと　探の装 改の戦闘データ
取らせてほしいな
なっ… 流子君！
Ryuuko!
You should worry about your
own skin, Mikisugi Aikurou.
（猿投山）
人のことを心配する余裕はないぞ
美木杉愛九郎
Ryuuko, snap out of it! Ryuuko!
（鮮血）流子！
しっかりしろ 流子！
（鮮血）フン！
Ryuuko, catch!
流子ちゃん これ！
Stop it, Mankanshoku.
（蟇郡）よせ満艦飾
Take your hands off that scissor.
そのハサミから手を離せ
I show none who stand against me
any mercy. Not even you.
でないと容赦しない
たとえお前だろうとな
Are you all right, Ryuuko?
（鮮血）大丈夫か流子
（流子）なんとかね
Yeah, somehow.
Do you wish to end this here in Osaka?
（皐月）
この大阪の地で決着をつけるか
Ryuuko, trust me.
（鮮血）流子 私に懸けろ
（流子）何？
What?
（鮮血）私を信じてくれ 友達なら
（流子）ああ わかった
If we are friends,
put your faith in me.
All right. You got it.
Using your Godrobe as a blade?
Impressive, but pointless.
神衣を剣にするか
だが無駄なあがきだ
Junketsu cannot be cut so easily!
それで純潔は斬れぬ
I'm well aware of that!
うおお〜 おりゃ〜！
（皐月）バカな
Impossible!
Nice job, Senketsu.
よくやった 鮮血
All the blood I had sucked up
was collected in the blade.
（鮮血）
吸ってきた流子の血を剣に集めた
一か八かだったがウマくいったな
It was an all-or-nothing
gamble, but it worked.
You heard him. This blade can
cut your Junketsu, can it not?
（流子）
というわけだ お前の純潔も
この刀なら斬れるんじゃないか？
Indeed, but not before my Junketsu
pierces through your Godrobe.
（皐月）
ああ だが私の純潔なら
お前の神衣を貫ける
へっ 相打ち覚悟ってわけか あ？
Mutually assured destruction... Huh?
Withdraw your troops, Kiryuuin.
Do that, and I'll lower the sword.
兵を引け 鬼龍院
そうすれば私も刀を引く
Are you sure?
いいのか？
ここで父親の敵を取らなくて
You would be failing
to avenge your father.
I won't sacrifice the lives
of others to achieve my goal.
そのために人の命を
犠牲にはできない
You wish to trade my life
for theirs, do you?
（皐月）
あやつらと私の命が引き換えか
ずいぶんと安く見られたものだ
I'm insulted at how low
a price you've put on me.
Lady Satsuki, please stand down!
皐月様 ここはお引きください
あなたは大望のある身
Yours is a noble goal!
You mustn't fall here
out of mere stubbornness!
つまらぬ意地で
ここで倒れるわけにはいかない
See? He agrees with me.
（流子）ああいう声もあるぜ！
All students, stand down!
全生徒 戦闘をやめろ！
We are returning to Honnouji Academy!
本能字学園に帰還する
Ryuuko, you dropped this!
（マコ）流子ちゃん 落とし物だよ
（流子）ありがとう
Thanks.
Kiryuuin, maybe it's true that you've
mastered that Junketsu of yours.
鬼龍院 確かにお前はその純潔を
着こなしているのかもしれない
だが お前は１人だ
But you're alone.
And you are not?
貴様は違うというのか？
No. Senketsu and I are two in one.
ああ 私と鮮血 ２人で１人だ
Are you suggesting you've formed a
symbiotic relationship with the Life Fibers?
（皐月）
生命戦維と共生するというのか？
それは夢物語だ
That is a fairy tale.
（流子）何だと？
Come again?
I shall leave Bakuzan
in your care to mark today's battle.
縛斬(ばくざん) 貴様に預けておくぞ
今日の戦いの証しだ
Kiryuuin.
（流子）鬼龍院
What?
貴様
The Kiryuuin Satsuki I know
（流子）鬼龍院皐月という女
isn't so petty a woman that she'd rescind an order
she'd given just because she got her sword back.
刀が戻ったぐらいで
一度出した命令を変えるほど—
小さな人間じゃないはずだ
フン
（黄長瀬）おっ
（美木杉）何！
What the?!
Did you forget about me?
（蛇崩）私の存在を忘れてた？
They call us the Four Devas
because there's four of us!
四天王は４人いるから四天王なのよ
Lady Satsuki, as per your orders,
I have destroyed the Nudist Beach base.
（蛇崩）皐月様 ご指示どおり—
ヌーディストビーチの基地を
破壊してまいりました
（皐月）ご苦労
Well done.
With that, we have crushed
the fools who opposed us.
これで我々に敵対する愚か者の
戦力は潰した
The objective of the Big Three
Battlefield Trip has been fulfilled.
三都制圧襲学旅行の目的は
完遂された
帰還命令を変更する必要は何もない
There is no need whatsoever to
rescind my order to return home.
I commend your valiant efforts,
Matoi Ryuuko.
貴様の健闘はたたえよう 纏流子
But you merely caught me by surprise.
だが奇襲は奇襲だ 次はないぞ！
The same tactic will not work twice!
This battle cost us most of
Nudist Beach's forces.
（黄長瀬）
これでヌーディストビーチの
戦力の大半は失われた
Still, we should be
grateful that we're alive.
（美木杉）
それでも命があるだけ まだマシだ
You fought Kiryuuin Satsuki to a draw.
鬼龍院皐月と引き分けるとは
よく戦ったね 流子君
That was impressive, Ryuuko.
Come with me.
（美木杉）おいで
（流子）えっ
I gave you my word.
約束だったからね
It's time to tell you everything.
全てを話すときが来た
This is a world tailored to someone's whims and fancies
dareka ga katteni kimeta readymade na
I'll break free of its shackles
kyou wo nugisutete
And sprint toward my goal
hadashi de hashitte iku
Even if I lose my way
machigattatte
Or trip and fall
korondatte
Those wounds will still create
surimuita itami mo
An original future for me
original na ashita ni naru
I hold my destiny in my own hands
tsukiageta kono te ni nigirishimeta
And it shines ever so brightly
chikai ga hikari ni natte
So until the day I reach you
itsuka kimi ni todoku sono shunkan made
I don't have the time to sit around crying
naiteru hima nante nai kara
My burning passion pours out from within me
hamidashite shimatta atsui omoi ga
And shines like a star in the night sky
yozora de kagayaki dasu
I think I now understand
umarete kita imi ga
Why I was born
wakatta ki ga shita
I'll make all of my dreams come true
negaigoto wa zenbu kono te de
With my own hands
kanaeru
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
After her battle with Satsuki,
Ryuuko learns her father's secret at last!
（鮮血）
皐月との戦いの果て
ついに流子は父の秘密を知る
SECRET
...That secret is...
その秘密とは…
ああ とても時間が足りない
SECRET
Oh, there's not nearly enough time!
NOT NEARLY
ENOUGH TIME
For the full story, search online for the
web version of the KILL la KILL preview!
詳しくはＷｅｂ版予告で
“キルラキル”で検索
WEB VERSION
OF THE PREVIEW
Next time on KILL la KILL,
"The Girl Can't Help It".
次回 キルラキル
「女はそれを我慢できない」
EPISODE 15
THE GIRL
CAN'T HELP IT